https://www.adventuresmithexplorations.com/company/privacy-policy/

open nav open search
close menu Favorites Choose Your Adventure Choose Your Adventure Trip Finder Ship Finder Deal FinderDestinations Destinations North America North America Alaska Canada Pacific Northwest Baja California Hawaii Central America Central America Costa Rica Panama Belize Guatemala Caribbean South America South America Galapagos Islands Amazon Peru Ecuador Patagonia Chile Asia/Pacific Asia/Pacific Australia New Zealand Pacific Islands Southeast Asia Indonesia Polar Regions Polar Regions Antarctica Arctic Europe Europe Northern Europe Mediterranean Our Style Our Style About Our Cruises About Our Cruises Cruise FAQ Cruise Reviews Cruise Guide About Our Land Tours Charter Cruises Custom Travel Family Travel Company CompanyAdventureSmith Explorations is the global leader in small ship, adventure cruise vacations. Small, sustainable travel options are at our core. Company founder Todd Smith helped pioneer the concept of wilderness cruising, and since founding AdventureSmith in 2003, he and his team have matched guests with the top names in small ship cruising as well as intimate, boutique ships and lodges that may not make the radar of most travelers. Why Book with Us Conservation Crew Our Partners Our Partners Operator Conservation Industry Press & Awards Blog Contact Us
1-877-620-2875
1-877-620-2875
Search our Site
View Wishlist
Press enter or click the search icon to start search search
close searchPrivacy PolicyAdventureSmith Explorations is committed to protecting the personal information that you share with us. This Privacy Policy is designed to inform you about our information collection practices, including how we collect information; what information we collect; why we collect information; how we use the information we collect; with whom we share the information we collect; how you can access, modify or delete your personal information; and what kinds of security we use to protect the information you provide. Before providing any personally identifiable information to AdventureSmith Explorations, you should read this entire policy. Use of our website www.AdventureSmithExplorations.com, communicating with us, or using the services offered by us constitutes your agreement to the terms of this privacy policy. If the terms of this policy are not acceptable to you, do not provide any personally identifiable information to us. If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at privacy@adventuresmithexplorations.com.What personal information does AdventureSmith Explorations collect and use?AdventureSmith Explorations collects personal information including but not limited to full name, age, addresses, phone numbers, email addresses, passport information, medical information, dietary information, insurance details, nationality, residence, travel and accommodation preferences, comments you provide to us, destination information, credit card and/or other payment information, trip evaluations, travel journals, and photos. We also collect details of any group members with whom you are traveling and tell us about; other travel information such as flight information, hotel reservations, transfers, or other arrangements as needed to coordinate travel; and any other information that you may provide to us. Our website and automated marketing technologies may collect non-personally identifiable information such as IP address and/or statistics about what parts of our website are most popular, where website traffic comes from, or similar information.AdventureSmith Explorations collects personal information from agents and agencies as needed to allow agents to book AdventureSmith Explorations’ trips and to be properly credited for bookings and as needed to communicate and execute bookings with AdventureSmith Explorations. Information may include name, employer information, email address, business phone number, business addresses, and other personal information you provide to us. If you are an agent traveling with AdventureSmith Explorations, we may also collect the personal information in the previous paragraph in order to facilitate and arrange your travel.AdventureSmith Explorations collects personal information from individuals applying for employment to the extent necessary to identify the individual and evaluate their suitability for the position applied for. This information may include name, contact information, educational and employment background, and any other information provided in a cover letter, resume, or other written or oral communication from you.Why is personal information collected? What do we do with your information?1. To provide our servicesIf you make an inquiry or booking with AdventureSmith Explorations, we use your personal information to provide you with information about our services and/or to provide the services and/or products you have requested. We may use personal information to answer your request for information about our trips, to register you to receive newsletters with your consent, to make a booking or bookings on your behalf including with third parties, to provide you with information about our company and/or services, and to receive and implement feedback on those services. Personal information allows us to understand your needs as a customer and determine eligibility for our products and services; to inform you about our products and services or those of our partners that may be of interest to you; to provide ongoing service and support; to ensure the safety and security of our travelers and products; to carry out internal accounting and administration of our business; and to comply with laws, regulations, and the like.If you make an inquiry or booking with AdventureSmith Explorations, we will share your personal information with third-party suppliers and service providers to the extent necessary to provide you with a proposal and/or perform our contract with you, and to the extent necessary for the pursuit of our legitimate interests. For example, if you make an inquiry or booking with us, we must necessarily share your name, age, travel preferences and other personal information in order to obtain availability, costs, bookings, and reservations. Those third parties may have different information practices, which will be governed by their privacy policies, which we recommend you read as well.Because it is necessary to our contract with you and to the implementation of our legitimate interests you must also consent to our sharing this information. If you fail to consent, we may not be able provide our services to you. By making an inquiry or booking, you hereby consent to our sharing your information with third parties as described in this privacy policy. While you may withdraw your consent at any time, we are still able to share your information pursuant to the lawful purposes stated in the previous paragraph.  We disclose personal information to third party whose services are required for us to provide our services to you. Depending on the particular services we provide to you, we will disclose your information to the following types of third parties:Hotels and lodging operatorsTour operators, outfitters, and guidesCruise linesAirlinesGround transportation companiesTravel insurance companiesPayment processors2. Data analytics and marketingAlso, to the extent necessary for the pursuit of our legitimate interests, AdventureSmith Explorations and our authorized service providers such as marketing agencies and data analytics providers will use your personal information to analyze your business with us, including your inquiries, bookings and preferences, which we may use to review, develop and improve our products and services; improve our customers’ experiences; and for internal market research, strategic development, and statistical analysis. In addition, we use systems that collect anonymous information such as which web pages are visited and how long each page is viewed. We cannot tie this information back to any individual user, unless the user contacts us.We disclose personal information to third party processors whose services are highly useful and assist in the functioning of our Services, including for the following specific purposes:Anonymous website usage tracking and marketing dataCloud data storageEmail marketingWebsite functionalityWeb form integration3. In the event of a business transferIn the event that ownership of us was to change as a result of a merger, acquisition, or transfer to another company, your information may be transferred. If such a transfer results in a material change in the use of your information, you will be provided notice (which may be via updates to this page) about the choices you have to decline to permit such a transfer.4. For administrative and legal reasonsIn addition, we will disclose your personal information when we are required to do so by law or believe in good faith that such disclosures are required to: (1) comply with the law or with legal process, including but not limited to lawful requests by public authorities that may be made to meet national security or law enforcement requirements; (2) enforce any legal agreements between you and us, including without limitation, out Terms & Conditions for your use of our services; (3) protect your safety or security; (4) protect the safety or security of the Company, our services, our property, and our employees; or (5) protect the safety or security of third parties. Among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions.How do we collect personal information?AdventureSmith Explorations collects personal information in two ways: actively and passively. Active collection of personal information includes website form submissions, newsletter sign up forms, sending us a message via email, entering a competition, calling our representatives on the phone, speaking with a representative in our office or at a trade show, communicating with us via social media or if you have asked another agent to make an inquiry on your behalf. If you provide information to us about another person other than yourself, such as other members of your travel party, you must ensure that they understand how their information will be used and that they have given their permission for you to disclose it to us and for you to allow us and our service providers to use it. Active collection can include both personally identifiable information (name, email, phone number, etc.) and non-personally identifiable information (destination, trip of interest, etc.).Our website features secure forms where users can request information, sign up to receive electronic updates, alerts and other information regarding our products and services. In order to use these forms, you must provide us with an email address, phone number and country of residence. In completing your registration, we may also ask for optional information such as your destination of interest, so we may serve you better.Passive information collection refers to instances in which we collect non-identifiable information that you have not actively provided such as IP address, the type of web browser or operating system you use, the date and time of your visit, the specific pages you visit and the address of the website you visited prior to entering www.AdventureSmithExplorations.com. We may link this passively collected non-personally identifiable information with the personally identifiable information you have actively provided elsewhere on our website. Our website uses cookies. A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that a website sends to your computer web browser. While you visit our website, the cookie may be used to track the activities of your browser as well as provide you with a consistent, more efficient experience. Cookies may be used so that you do not have to fill in the same information again and again. We may use cookies to measure website usage such as entry and exit points of visitors, how many people visit a certain page, and the details of searches performed. If you are making a purchase or payment or completing a traveler information form or evaluation form, we may use cookies to keep track of the transaction from one page to the next.  We do not store any personal information in the cookie.Data Security – How is your information protected?The security and integrity of your personal information is very important to us. All personal information is stored in secure databases to prevent unauthorized access. Passwords, encryption devices and firewalls protect these databases. Access to your personal information is limited to authorized employees of AdventureSmith Explorations and any of the third-party suppliers who require information to provide the travel services you have requested (such as airlines, transportation services, cruise lines, hotels, activity providers, and tour guides who deliver our products and services).Although we take precautions to protect the personal information you provided to us, no system is 100% secure or error free. Therefore, we do not and cannot guarantee the security or accuracy of the information we gather. How do I access, amend or delete my personal information?We do not seek to collect personal information from you that you do not want collected. However, certain information may be required in order for us to deliver the services you have requested. If you do not provide the personal information we request, we may not be able to deliver the services you have requested, which may mean you will not be able to participate in our trips. If you have paid a deposit and later refuse to provide necessary personal information required to deliver the service for which the deposit was paid, (for example a cruise which requires your name, birthdate, and may require a personally identifying number (such as a driver’s license or passport number), you may not be entitled to a refund for that service. Please contact us if you have any questions about providing or not providing personal information when booking your travel or otherwise working with AdventureSmith Explorations.  When you submit personal information to us, whether such information is required or optional, that information will be subject to this Privacy Policy.1. Unsubscribe from direct marketingShould you wish to unsubscribe from marketing communications via email or otherwise wish to not have your data used for direct marketing purposes, you may opt out by clicking on the “unsubscribe” button at the bottom of any AdventureSmith Explorations newsletter or marketing email. Should you wish to unsubscribe via phone, mail or email please call us at 1-800-728-2875 or 530-583-1775, email us at unsubscribe@adventuresmithexplorations.com, or write to us at 40169 Truckee Airport Road, Suite 201, Truckee CA 96161.2. Shine the LightUnder California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-.84, California residents are entitled to ask for a notice identifying the categories of personal customer information that we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a current customer and California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to: AdventureSmith Explorations, Inc., ATTN: Privacy Team, 40169 Truckee Airport Road, Suite 201, Truckee CA 96161.3. Access, correction, and deletion  We work hard to ensure that your personal information is accurate, current and complete. Accordingly, we provide you with reasonable access to your personal information to correct errors or delete the information you have provided. If you wish to review, correct or delete your personal information please contact our privacy office by phone at 1-800-728-2875 or 530-583-1775, email us at privacy@adventuresmithexplorations.com, or write to us at 40169 Truckee Airport Road, Suite 201, Truckee CA 96161. Please note if you have booked through a travel agency, you will need to contact that agent or agency directly regarding the access, correction or deletion of any personal information they may hold.For consumers, except for data analytics and marketing purposes as described in this privacy policy, we will not process your data once your travel with us is complete. For travel agents and third party suppliers, we will retain and process your data for as long as we are engaged in an on-going relationship with you (as determined by us in our sole discretion). For employment applicants, we will retain your personal data for up to one year. You may contact us at any time and request that personal data be deleted from our database and we will honor your request as long as we do not need to retain the information for legitimate business or legal purposes. Except as otherwise stated in this policy, we will retain your data indefinitely.4. Other rightsDepending on the law that applies where you live, you may have additional rights, such as the right to request that we send your information to another organization of your choice (where technically feasible) and, that we restrict our processing of your data.Questions or complaintsIf you have any questions or complaints about our collection, disclosure, use or dealings with your personal information, or if you believe we are in violation of applicable privacy legislation, please contact us at privacy@adventuresmithexplorations.com, or write to us at 40169 Truckee Airport Road, Suite 201, Truckee CA 96161. We take all complaints seriously and will review your complaint within 15 business days and provide you with a written response. If this response is not satisfactory you may contact the data privacy authority in your local jurisdiction, if one exists.  Effective 6/20/18 Share Us.
Subscribe
Stay Inspired.New small ship cruises, adventure trips, ships & the best deals at your fingertips.Name*
First
Last
Email* Country of Residence (Required in order to comply with privacy laws)*United States of America - USAfghanistan - AFAland Islands - AXAlbania - ALAlgeria - DZAmerican Samoa - ASAndorra - ADAngola - AOAnguilla - AIAntarctica - AQAntigua and Barbuda - AGArgentina - ARArmenia - AMAruba - AWAustralia - AUAustria - ATAzerbaijan - AZBahamas - BSBahrain - BHBangladesh - BDBarbados - BBBelarus - BYBelgium - BEBelize - BZBenin - BJBermuda - BMBhutan - BTBolivia - BOBosnia and Herzegovina - BABotswana - BWBouvet Island - BVBrazil - BRBritish Virgin Islands - VGBritish Indian Ocean Territory - IOBrunei Darussalam - BNBulgaria - BGBurkina Faso - BFBurundi - BICambodia - KHCameroon - CMCanada - CACape Verde - CVCayman Islands - KYCentral African Republic - CFChad - TDChile - CLChina - CNHong Kong, SAR China - HKMacao, SAR China - MOChristmas Island - CXCocos (Keeling) Islands - CCColombia - COComoros - KMCongo (Brazzaville) - CGCongo, (Kinshasa) - CDCook Islands - CKCosta Rica - CRCôte d'Ivoire - CICroatia - HRCuba - CUCyprus - CYCzech Republic - CZDenmark - DKDjibouti - DJDominica - DMDominican Republic - DOEcuador - ECEgypt - EGEl Salvador - SVEquatorial Guinea - GQEritrea - EREstonia - EEEthiopia - ETFalkland Islands (Malvinas) - FKFaroe Islands - FOFiji - FJFinland - FIFrance - FRFrench Guiana - GFFrench Polynesia - PFFrench Southern Territories - TFGabon - GAGambia - GMGeorgia - GEGermany - DEGhana - GHGibraltar - GIGreece - GRGreenland - GLGrenada - GDGuadeloupe - GPGuam - GUGuatemala - GTGuernsey - GGGuinea - GNGuinea-Bissau - GWGuyana - GYHaiti - HTHeard and Mcdonald Islands - HMHoly See (Vatican City State) - VAHonduras - HNHungary - HUIceland - ISIndia - INIndonesia - IDIran, Islamic Republic of - IRIraq - IQIreland - IEIsle of Man - IMIsrael - ILItaly - ITJamaica - JMJapan - JPJersey - JEJordan - JOKazakhstan - KZKenya - KEKiribati - KIKorea (North) - KPKorea (South) - KRKuwait - KWKyrgyzstan - KGLao PDR - LALatvia - LVLebanon - LBLesotho - LSLiberia - LRLibya - LYLiechtenstein - LILithuania - LTLuxembourg - LUMacedonia, Republic of - MKMadagascar - MGMalawi - MWMalaysia - MYMaldives - MVMali - MLMalta - MTMarshall Islands - MHMartinique - MQMauritania - MRMauritius - MUMayotte - YTMexico - MXMicronesia, Federated States of - FMMoldova - MDMonaco - MCMongolia - MNMontenegro - MEMontserrat - MSMorocco - MAMozambique - MZMyanmar - MMNamibia - NANauru - NRNepal - NPNetherlands - NLNetherlands Antilles - ANNew Caledonia - NCNew Zealand - NZNicaragua - NINiger - NENigeria - NGNiue - NUNorfolk Island - NFNorthern Mariana Islands - MPNorway - NOOman - OMPakistan - PKPalau - PWPalestinian Territory - PSPanama - PAPapua New Guinea - PGParaguay - PYPeru - PEPhilippines - PHPitcairn - PNPoland - PLPortugal - PTPuerto Rico - PRQatar - QARéunion - RERomania - RORussian Federation - RURwanda - RWSaint-Barthélemy - BLSaint Helena - SHSaint Kitts and Nevis - KNSaint Lucia - LCSaint-Martin (French part) - MFSaint Pierre and Miquelon - PMSaint Vincent and Grenadines - VCSamoa - WSSan Marino - SMSao Tome and Principe - STSaudi Arabia - SASenegal - SNSerbia - RSSeychelles - SCSierra Leone - SLSingapore - SGSlovakia - SKSlovenia - SISolomon Islands - SBSomalia - SOSouth Africa - ZASouth Georgia and the South Sandwich Islands - GSSouth Sudan - SSSpain - ESSri Lanka - LKSudan - SDSuriname - SRSvalbard and Jan Mayen Islands - SJSwaziland - SZSweden - SESwitzerland - CHSyrian Arab Republic (Syria) - SYTaiwan, Republic of China - TWTajikistan - TJTanzania, United Republic of - TZThailand - THTimor-Leste - TLTogo - TGTokelau - TKTonga - TOTrinidad and Tobago - TTTunisia - TNTurkey - TRTurkmenistan - TMTurks and Caicos Islands - TCTuvalu - TVUganda - UGUkraine - UAUnited Arab Emirates - AEUnited Kingdom - GBUnited States of America - USUS Minor Outlying Islands - UMUruguay - UYUzbekistan - UZVanuatu - VUVenezuela (Bolivarian Republic) - VEViet Nam - VNVirgin Islands, US - VIWallis and Futuna Islands - WFWestern Sahara - EHYemen - YEZambia - ZMZimbabwe - ZW
North America
Alaska
Canada
Pacific Northwest
Baja California
Hawaii
Central America
Costa Rica
877-620-2875
© 2020 AdventureSmith ExplorationsAll rights reserved. No part of this site may be reproduced without our written permission.test message View Wishlist
Contact UsWishlistNewsletter
This site uses cookies to improve your experience. Learn More.Got it!
